http://www.poyntonnetball.co.uk/cookies-privacy

Cookies and Privacy Policy
Privacy PolicyPoynton Netball Club is committed to ensuring that personal information is held fairly, lawfully and securely in accordance with data protection laws.This policy covers the different elements of personal information we collect from you, what we do with the information, how long we will hold it, what we won’t do with the information, as well as what rights you have.Introduction to Data ProtectionWe have an obligation under Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament – the General Data Protection Regulation (‘GDPR’) to provide you with information about how and why we use your data. We recognise our obligations and your legal rights set out in the GDPR. We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy by complying with the principles of the GDPR.Who are ‘we’?In this policy, whenever you see the words ‘we’, ‘us’ or ‘our’, it refers to the Poynton Netball Club.Data Protection OfficerPoynton Netball Club does not have a Data Protection Officer. However, for information and queries about data protection compliance, email: poynton.netball.club@gmail.comAmendments to our Privacy PolicyIf we amend our privacy policy, any changes will be published on our website. If necessary, this will be brought to your attention.What is personal data?‘Personal data’ means any information relating to a living individual (‘data subject’) who can be identified, directly or indirectly by the information.The types of personal data we MAY collect:The data we collect about you will vary, depending on our relationship with you. Below are examples of the sorts of data that we may collect:Full nameContact information (home address, email address, telephone numbers)Date of birth and/or age;Special categories of data such as medical history or race or ethnicity, disability or sexual orientation;Family, lifestyle or social circumstances;Next of kin and emergency contact information;Imagery in video and/or photographic form and voice recordings;Criminal convictions and offences;Records of participation at events/sessions/competition;Records of spectator attendance at events or competitions hosted by Poynton Netball Club;Records of enquiries and other correspondence with you;How we use your personal informationWe collect, store and process personal data for several purposes, mainly: our membership, programme and course administration; pathway, event and competition management; financial accounting; and marketing. We will not use any of the information that we collect from you, or about you, for any purpose other than those listed in this document or for purposes that are similar. If we would like to use your personal data in any other way, we will present you with relevant information at the point at which one of these additional purposes arises.The GDPR provides that legally we might hold and process your information for any of the following four reasons and we have included below a summary of what that means for Poynton Netball Club and how we might use information you provide to us:Where required to perform a CONTRACT.For example:To administer and manage our relationship with affiliated members. For example, when given personal information either directly or via a Club Secretary during the affiliation process;To send affiliated members information which is included within their membership benefits package;To administer our relationship with people attending our programmes and to send them information about the programme;To administer attendance on any programmes, competitions, events or training courses and to enable online assessment (where applicable);To fulfil our contractual relationship with clients, sponsors and suppliers.Where required to comply with our LEGAL OBLIGATIONS. For example:To comply with health and safety requirements. For example, to ensure the safe running of netball sessions and to enable adaptations as required;To comply with safeguarding requirements. For example, working with children or vulnerable adults;To ensure we are offering equitable access to our services to avoid discrimination; andFor the prevention of fraud and other criminal activities.Where there is a LEGITIMATE INTEREST.For example:To correspond and to answer queries and complaints;To create a better understanding of players, supporters, customers or visitors. We may process the personal data of those that engage with Poynton Netball Club for the purposes of research. This is to ensure that we are offering the best service that we can, to understand trends and enable us to improve delivery of the sport. We use the information to create aggregated summary statistics only.  From time to time, we may contact those groups listed above to take part in additional research to support the development and improvement of the sport. However, there is no obligation to take part in the research. Poynton Netball Club employees, or an external processor on our behalf, may carry out this research. For young people age under 16 we will seek parental or guardian consent;To arrange for any trips or transportation of officials, or volunteers to events;To ensure understanding of the coaching and officiating workforce available;To conduct performance reviews, manage performance and determine performance requirements of our officials and coaches and to make decisions about progression and accreditation status; andTo comply with awarding bodies’ accreditation obligations; andTo administer and monitor attendance at events and competitions.Where you have provided CONSENT.For example:We may use and process your personal information where you have consented for us to do so for the following purposes:Promoting the sport, our events, opportunities, services and membership packages;Promoting our sponsors or partners’ events or services; andSending newsletters.Retaining your information
If we collect your personal information, the length of time that we retain it is determined by a number of factors, including the purpose for which we use that information and to comply with our other legal obligations (apart from GDPR). We maintain a Retention Schedule, which records approved retention periods, the reasoning for the retention period and end of life treatment. Some of these retention periods are currently being defined by us and an update of this privacy policy will be added to our website once they have been formally approved.We do not retain personal information in an identifiable format for longer than is necessary. Where you have consented for us to retain your data, we will only hold the data for the duration of your consent.ChildrenChildren’s data are collected and processed in accordance with the information below. Parents and guardians are expected to ensure that the children they are responsible for are aware of how their personal data will be processed by us.We require parental or guardian consent to process personal data of any child under the age of 14.Using your information for marketingWe only send marketing information to you if you have explicitly agreed to our doing so or have requested it and we will only do so in the way(s) you have agreed to. You can withdraw consent at any time.See below for more information.Marketing information covers information about tickets to events, special offers, opportunities, products and services and other commercial information.In connection with information about tickets, special offers, opportunities, products and services and other commercial information, the categories have been divided into two groups:from Poynton Netball Clubfrom Poynton Netball Club about its sponsors and partnersIf you want to receive information from either of these two groups but haven’t yet requested it, you can do so by emailing poynton.netball.club@gmail.com.Withdrawing consentIf we contact you by email, every message we send will include a link to opt out of receiving future messages if you change your mind. If we contact you by other means and you want to change how – or if – you receive our communications, please email poynton.netball.club@gmail.com.Sharing your personal data and data processingWe only share personal data where we are required by law or with our suppliers or sub-contractors who carry out work for us and who you have given us permission to share it with. Other than the circumstances set out above, information about you will not be passed to a third party for any other purposes. All our suppliers and sub-contractors are required by their own data sharing agreements or contracts to treat your data as carefully as we would, to use it only as instructed, and to allow us to check that they do this.Organisations we share your personal data with:County Netball Associations;Regional Netball Associations;Leagues;Affiliated netball clubs;Companies, sub-contractors and other persons who help us to provide our programmes, products and services (e.g. Leisure centres where our programme are run);Data processors: for example, market research organisations, education and training providers, professional services, legal, financial, merchandise and information technologies who help to improve our products or services.
Where the law requires it. We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to comply with any legal obligation; to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Poynton Netball Club customers, or others, including exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction; andAnyone else where we have your consent.ProfilingPoynton Netball Club does not perform any profiling that has legal or significant effect nor any automated decision making.International transferThe personal information we collect may be transferred to and stored in countries outside of the UK and the European Union. Some of these jurisdictions require different levels of protection in respect of personal information and, in certain instances, the laws in those countries may be less protective than the jurisdiction you are resident. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is used only in accordance with this privacy notice and applicable data protection laws and is respected and kept secure. Where a third party processes your data on our behalf we will put in place appropriate safeguards as required under data protection laws.Google Cloud Platform is used for Google Docs. Google Cloud Platform subscribes to the EU-US Privacy Shield which is approved by the EU in relation to data protection practices. Their registration can be reviewed on the Privacy Shield website www.privacyshield.gov/list.Information SecurityWhere we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password, which enables you to access certain parts of our website, or membership portal, it is your responsibility to safeguard your password against the possibility that others may use it to gain unauthorised access. Do not store your password anywhere, in written or electronic form, or give it to someone else. Please let poynton.netball.club@gmail.com
know if any record containing your password is lost or stolen or if you think there has been a possibility that your security has been breached.More on Information SecurityWe do our very best to keep personal information secure wherever we collect personal data online. We place a great importance on the security of all personally identifiable information associated with our members, supporters, customers and users. We will take all steps reasonably necessary including policies, procedures and security features to ensure that information about you is treated securely and protected from unauthorised and unlawful access and used in accordance with this privacy policy. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of personal data under our control or being transferred, we use our best efforts to try to prevent this.Our website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of third parties. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not expect any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.What we don’t do with your informationWe never sell or share your information with other organisations to use for their own purposes.Your rightsThe GDPR grants you certain rights (‘information rights’) which we summarise below.Right of access:You have the right to obtain confirmation from Poynton Netball Club as to whether or not personal data concerning you are being processed, and, where that is the case, you have the right to access that personal data.Right to rectification:You have the right to oblige Poynton Netball Club to rectify inaccurate personal data concerning you. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you have the right to have incomplete personal data completed by providing a supplementary statement.Right to erasure (right to be forgotten):You have the right (under certain circumstances, but not all) to oblige Poynton Netball Club to erase personal data concerning you.Right to restriction of processing:You have the right (under certain circumstances, but not all) to oblige Poynton Netball Club to restrict processing of your personal data. For example, you may request this if you are contesting the accuracy of personal data held about you.Right to data portability:You have the right (under certain circumstances, but not all) to oblige Poynton Netball Club to provide you with the personal data about you which you have provided to Poynton Netball Club in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format.You also have the right to oblige Poynton Netball Club to transmit the data to another controller. Right to withdraw consent:If the lawful basis for processing is consent, you have the right to withdraw that consent.Right to object to direct marketing:Where your personal data are processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to processing of your personal data for marketing, which includes profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing.Rights in relation to automated decision making and profiling:Poynton Netball Club does not perform any automated decision-making based on personal data that produces legal effects or similarly significantly affects you.Your right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authorityIf you wish to exercise any of your rights concerning your personal data, you should contact us at poynton.netball.club@gmail.comPoynton Netball Club is not a ‘public authority’ as defined under the Freedom of Information Act and we will not therefore respond to requests for information made under this Act.If you are not satisfied with the response you receive, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority. In the United Kingdom this is the Information Commissioner’s Office, Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AF, telephone: 0303 123 1113, email: casework@ico.org.uk.Cookies PolicyWhen you visit Poynton Netball Club’s website, you may provide us with two types of information.Personal InformationYou knowingly choose to disclose, that is collected on an individual basis and is used in accordance with our Privacy Policy.Website use information which is collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse the websites, and is used as set out in this Cookies Policy.A cookie is a small text file that our website stores on your web browser which can later be retrieved. These allow us to distinguish you from other users of the website, however this information does not allow us to identify you personally and you remain anonymous unless you have otherwise provided us with Personal Information.You can surf the website anonymously and access information without revealing your identity. However, in order to provide a better service, we use “cookies”; some of the cookies we use maybe essential for parts of the website to operate, others help us to provide you with a better browsing experience. Occasionally, we may also use ‘analytical’ cookies which allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors to our website to see how visitors move around the website. This helps us to improve the way our website works.We only use cookies from third parties in order is to support and enhance our website.You may delete and block all or some cookies, but as a result parts of our websites may not work correctly. Most web browsers allow some control of most cookies through the browser settings. You can set up your web browser to inform you when you receive a cookie, giving you the option whether or not to accept it.In certain cases, our websites may also employ flash cookies. Flash cookies are used to improve and enhance your web browsing experience.
Copyright 2018 by Poynton Netball Club.All rights reserved.
Cookies and Privacy Policy
Create your business website with
Website Builder.
Share by:
